

S-2, Gangotri Apt., B.B. Borkar road, Alto-Pororvorim, Goa, 403521, India

□ (+91) 8408996464 | ☑ rajatgovekar@gmail.com | 🏕 www.rojjot.in | 🖸 RAJATRG | 🛅 ROJJOT

Summary

Current Software Development Engineer at Rupeek Fintech Pvt. Ltf. 2+ years experience specializing in the backend development, full stack web development, and machine learning. Super nerd who loves Vim, Linux and OS X and enjoys to customize all of the development environment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Work Experience _____

Rupeek Fintech, Pvt. Ltd.

Bengaluru, India

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

Jun. 2019 - Present

- · Worked on logistics division of rupeek gold loans. Worked on tracking of collateral delivery and appraisals system. Worked on on boarding different lending partner on rupeek system and streamline gold delivery and release process
- Implemented several API micro services in Node.js in creation of loans of customer.
- · Built fully automated system to read different types of files consisting of customer loan and transaction information.(MERN stack)

Indian Institute of Technology, Delhi

New Delhi, India

- RESEARCH INTERN May. 2018 - July. 2018
- · Worked on Image Processing, Computer Vision and Machine Learning
- Main work was focussed on 3D Object classification using Neural Network
- · Implemnted a hybrid network of fisher vectors and neural network to classsify 3D objects(ModelNet dataset)

Education

National Institute of Technology, Goa

Ponda, Goa, India

B.Tech. in Electrical, Electronics and Communication Engineering -8.8 GPA

July. 2015 - May. 2019

Mushtifund Aryaan Higher Secondary School

Panaji, Goa,India

CLASS XII EXAMINATION (GBHSSE), 90.2 %

June. 2013 - May. 2015

L. D. Samant Memorial High School

Panaji, Goa,India

CLASS X EXAMINATION(GBHSSE), 92.33 %

2013

Projects

Coral Reefs Identification and Size Estimation

DonaPaula,Goa,India

NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF OCEONOGRAPHY

- The purpose of work was to detect and estimate the size of underwater coral reef from image frames using vision based technique. Deep learning architecture was used to detect the coral reefs. To extract the frames and build data set, real time underwater video was used
- Published the same work in IEEE explore Vision Based Underwater Environment Analysis: A Novel Approach to Estimate Size of Coral Reefs

Smart System to Guide Patients

Kolkata, India

SMART INDIA HACKATHON

April 2018

- Developed an app for indoor navigation for patients in hospitals.
- · App was built during Smart India Hacakthon, 2018 Grand Finale held at Kolkata under Ministry of Health and Family Welfare
- The app won 5th place and KPIT Innovation Award at the Hackathon among 50 teams that had been selcted among 10,000 participation

RAJATG · RÉSUMÉ MAY 1, 2021

Awards and Achievments

	2021	Extra Mile Award , Rupeek Fintech Pvt. Ltd for performing above and beyond normal expectations and from	Bengaluru, India
		my regular assignment in specific and recognizable way	bengalara, mala
	2018	5th , Smart India Hackathon Competition organised by MHRD and AICTE.(Team Leader)	Kolkata, India
	2019	Sponsorship Head, Saavyas 2018, the annual techno-cultural festival of NIT, GOA	Goa, India
	2015	Coordinator and Founding Member, QUANTA, The quiz club of NIT GOA	Goa, India
	2015	All India Rank, 32366(96.44%ile) in JEE(MAIN) and 18942(88.6%ile) in JEE(ADVANCED)	Goa,India

Skills_____

- Programming
 - Javascript, Nodejs
 Python, C/C++
 MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis
- Frameworks and Tools
 - ExpressJS,VueJS,SailsJSMongoDB Compass,PostBirdAWS Cloud

Hobbies and Intersets _____

Stock Market Trading, Image Processing, Acting, Reading Books, Playing Video games